Ah
Good morning, master.
Ah! Good morning, Master.
Good morning, Grandmaster Rudeus.
How are you today?
Good morning, Xenobah.
I'm good, Julie.
Huh?
Hey, good morning, Boss.
You're looking bright-eyed.
And bushy-chilled.
Meow! What's the big idea?
No-no-no-no.
Guess the Boss finally went into heat.
I bet it's because of my charm.
I'm a simple temptress.
If you became the Boss's woman, you would never run out of meat.
Rudeus, what's up with you?
How do you mean?
I don't know.
You just have this look about you.
Like you're bursting with confidence.
If I can have your attention, I guess I have an announcement.
Although I can't reveal the details right now,
I was cured of a long-term ailment yesterday.
Dang, I had no idea you were sick, Boss.
Yeah, is that why you never jumped our bones or anything?
Many heartfelt congratulations.
Although you could have confided in me at any time.
So that's it.
You must have struggled.
Congratulations, Rudeus.
The disease that plagued my first year at the University of Magic
is no more.
All thanks to Sylphie,
who gave me something precious to help me through it.
I finally feel human again.
Now he smells even more in heat!
He's a threat to the chastity of every one of us!
Keep your distance or you're lined up preggers!
How uncouth.
I'm a gentleman, you know.
If you were to date someone, Nanohoshi,
what kinds of things would you want or expect from them?
I take it that's your idea of small talk today?
Something like that.
All you ever do is chit-chat.
Would you take this seriously?
I'd like to get home as soon as I can.
And we'll work far more efficiently if you keep quiet.
Okay, don't get defensive.
I take it you've never been in love then?
Tch.
Of course I have.
Although,
we had a fight and I haven't seen him since.
Ah, right.
Nanohoshi was summoned in the middle of an argument.
Sorry.
You don't need to apologize.
Just work.
And if I like someone,
just spending time together is enough.
I've been sending the occasional letter to Paul to keep him updated.
And now that I'm cured,
I could work to reunite with my family.
But there's one more thing I want to embark on first.
I want to do right by Sylphie.
She helped me.
Now it's my turn to provide for her as a husband.
Oh.
Actually, wait.
How do you get married in this world?
Marriage, Master?
Weddings.
I just realized I don't know what's considered traditional.
Well, let me think.
You start with the house, right?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, you jump straight to a house?
Yeah, of course you do.
How can you get married if you don't even have a place to live?
Fair enough.
Paul and Zenith settled down in Buena Village as soon as they married, too.
It would be one thing if you married a well-to-do girl who already had a home of her own.
But if neither of you do, the man shows his worth by getting one.
Okay, a little culture shock there.
Understood.
Then a house will come first.
I'll go into town tomorrow to look at some.
Wait a sec.
You're already engaged?
Yeah.
Kinda.
To who?
To, uh, the person who cured my illness.
Keep your secrets, then.
But if she's a follower of Mealus, do let me know, okay?
I can't conduct a full service yet, but I can give a blessing.
Thanks.
I came in here without a plan.
I honestly have no idea how nice a place I should try to aim for.
Sylvie guards a princess, and work aside, they're good friends.
Which means Princess Ariel might come to visit from time to time.
So I guess we'll need a pretty nice place, then, won't we?
Maybe I should have brought Sylvie to get her input on all this.
No, no.
I've got to show her she can count on me.
A big house with plenty of rooms.
That doesn't cost too much.
Oh?
Oh.
What a lovely place.
It's a little big for two people, isn't it?
Maybe.
But its reputation drove down the price.
You said the housing authority thinks that it's cursed?
There are reports of a scraping sound in the middle of the night, and apparently its previous residents were murdered inside.
Did they try an exorcism?
The first party to do it was mangled, too, so the Adventurer's Guild took the job down.
The Mages Guild won't touch it either.
Talk about negligent.
That's why I called you two in.
Now then, on your guards, gentlemen, and let's get to it!
Huh.
Hey, what's your problem? Don't just start breaking things!
Pardon me. The door was warped and wouldn't open otherwise.
Huh.
Master, how shall we proceed?
We'll start on the ground floor here. Sweep the rooms counterclockwise.
Understood, Master.
Huh. You're being awfully official about this.
I am an A-ranked adventurer, and I'm gonna live here, so...
Alright. Yeah, I guess you are.
In that case, what do you want me to do?
If we do run into anything, I'd like you to attack with elementary divine magic.
Okay, I can do that.
When you come to, it's crazy.
Another try, God, I need you to do it.
Okay.
Hey, God.
Hi.
No signs of life.
But you wanted us to stay the night here, didn't you?
Yes. If that's still okay.
It'll be dark in here before too long.
Whatever's killing people is supposed to show up at night.
I'm guessing some kind of monster has made its lair here.
It shouldn't be that strong. High-ranked monsters won't come into town.
But you can't be too careful.
I'm a little worried about Julie.
Yeah, I've been worrying about Lise too.
I'm worried about Sylphie myself.
Sanopa.
Yes, Master?
You know, as soon as we finish this job, I'm getting married.
Yes. Let's sort this out quickly and throw a magnificent party to celebrate your matrimony.
Sounds like fun.
So you had better invite Lise and me.
Yeah, of course I will.
Oh, my God.
Oh.
Oh!
Rudeus, wake up!
I hear something!
Wake Sanobab for me.
Huh?
How's it look out there?
I can't see anything in the dark.
Let's sweep the house again.
Understood.
I want to put eyes on every nook and cranny,
so keep your wits about you.
Right.
Now all that's left is the basement.
Yeah.
What's the word?
No sign of anything.
Nothing.
Hmm.
Let's go back to the bedroom.
We can better prepare for an attack in there.
There's definitely something here.
Maybe it'll come to us.
Or maybe it'll wait until we're fast asleep again.
Now it could be lurking in here.
Stay on your guard.
Looks like the coast is clear, Master.
Hmm.
Yep, it's definitely gonna wait till we're asleep.
Fun exciting.
Huh?
Let's...
Let's find the
fire.
Annemerer.
Hmm?
Begone, you!
I'm a blessed child, you recall.
This won't even leave a scratch.
I call upon thee, God who blesses the land, our mother with bounty!
Visit divinity upon the foolish who defies the natural ways!
Exorcism!
I'll be.
That didn't do anything!
Get out of the way!
Zanobar!
Move!
Please wait, master!
No, that's enough!
I'll handle it!
No, master!
Wait!
I beg of you!
Thank you.
Now, back to the room.
Uh, yeah.
What?
I wasn't running away, okay?
The hallway was so narrow, I thought I'd be in the way.
That's true.
Good call.
I know.
I'm not gonna tease you.
Spooked me too, man.
I know.
You're not an immortal demon king or anything.
Just look at it, master.
Oh.
Is that... a doll?
Indeed.
And a magnificent one at that.
Okay.
I know you like dolls and everything, but come on.
I will not.
This doll was moving of its own accord.
A moving doll!
Yeah.
I guess it was.
How about that?
Robots, automata, and mecha maids.
Oh my.
That really is incredible!
I'm so glad you finally understand, master.
Well done, Xenobah.
Your keen eye for dolls has already surpassed mine.
Ah.
I recognized it as a doll the moment I laid eyes on it.
A magic moving doll, huh?
If we can figure out how it works, maybe we can make our own.
This one is wooden, but if we could animate a... silicone or something...
The possibilities...
What an amazing...
I find!
My heart is pounding out of my chest!
Oh yes.
Mine too.
I feel as though I may even weep.
What is wrong with you freaks?
Huh?
We've got more important things to worry about than a doll.
What could be more important than that?!
It moved entirely on its own!
Can you not see a grand significance?
I can just say you could still be a monster!
Xenobah, you can let go of him now.
But master...
Sorry, but Master Cliff has a point.
I mean...
The doll probably is our evil spirit.
Oh.
And it might not be alone.
We need to find that out.
And if we're lucky, we may find schematics for making them too.
Oh, yes! I see your point now!
Come on, let's figure out where that thing was hiding.
Huh.
There's an odd scrape on the floor here.
I wonder if the wall is actually...
Xenobah, will you give it a push?
With pleasure.
Pleasure.
Hm.
I knew it. A hidden door.
Cliff, come here a sec. Do you know what this pedestal is for?
I don't. Totally foreign to me.
What'd you find?
Uh...
Book?
And it seems to have something about the doll in it.
Looks like there might be magic circles somewhere on the body.
How can you tell that?
Uh...
I've been studying magical implements lately.
I've seen a lot of similar diagrams.
That's fascinating.
Whoever this room belonged to either made the doll or was studying it.
Seems like it was programmed in some way to protect the house.
At least, that would explain all our unlucky murder victims anyway.
And with all this stuff untouched and gathering dust,
I assume the owner must have been able to do this.
It seems to be a good idea.
And with all this stuff untouched and gathering dust,
I assume the owner must have died suddenly.
In any case,
Looks like that was the only doll in the house.
Yes.
In other words,
Case closed.
Thank you.
Seriously.
I don't know what I would have done if it wasn't for you two.
Don't mention it.
We're not strangers.
But, um, what are you gonna do with all that stuff?
I'm not sure.
I guess I'll borrow a spare lab to study it and...
Master?
Yeah? What's up?
Might I convince you to leave the research of this moving doll entirely to me?
You want to take points on all of it?
My monopool is beyond abysmal.
And my hands are clumsy.
Take for instance the red dragon figurine we're making for Julie.
All I have accomplished is being in the way.
I make the work drag on forever.
Deciphering the handwriting in the journal will probably take me some time.
The research would undoubtedly proceed faster in your hands alone, Master.
And yet...
What if the doll decides to go berserk again while you're studying it?
I can handle roughhousing.
I'm no stranger to it.
Well, obviously, but...
Master, I beg you.
Hear me.
When your plans finally bear fruit,
I want to have contributed more than just money.
I swear I will prove myself useful to you.
Please, Master. Please entrust this research to me!
Very well.
Xanoba, the doll's all yours.
You truly mean it?
I will say, someone kept this secret for a reason, so be careful.
I cannot thank you enough!
Well, keep it under control, whatever you do.
We don't need that thing rampaging.
Least of all at school.
I made an unexpected find, and I've got the home of my dreams.
My, whatever do you want to show me out here, Rudy?
I simply can't wait to find out.
Your delivery is so wooden, Sylphie.
I wonder, could it be that you did some snooping around and already know what your surprise is?
Why?
What do you mean?
I don't know what you're talking about.
I had the contractors get something close to your original hair color for the roof.
I always really liked your hair.
Even if you didn't.
Huh?
Oh gosh, you're right!
What do you say?
Wanna come inside and see the rest?
Oh, my god.
Our bedroom.
It's the only room done on this floor so far.
Goodness.
Why do we need such a huge bed?
You really have to ask?
So I can savor every bite of you, of course!
Oh, that makes sense.
I almost forgot.
Uh, Sylphie.
Oh, yes?
I promised to marry you, but are we rushing into it?
Like, what comes next?
I bought this house for us to start, but beside that, we still have so much to talk over.
Oh, well, however many kids you want is fine with me.
Okay.
I'm definitely happy to hear it, but what about guarding Princess Ariel?
We've still got another two years in this country at least.
And we aren't planning to rush back to Asura the second we graduate.
So, um…
Sorry.
That's not very fair.
You deserve someone who can settle down.
You've provided such a beautiful home.
But am I really good enough?
Sylphie helped give me back a part of myself.
And she used her body to do it.
It was her very first time, and I was rough.
But if she was afraid…
She never showed any sign of it that I could see.
And she smiled at me in the morning.
That's what finally made me feel whole again.
So if she isn't good enough, no one is.
I have no right to be your wife, do I?
Sylphie, you're mine no matter what!
Oh, yes, yes!
Of course!
I'm yours, Rudy!
So, please, will you marry me?
Ah!
Yes!
I got the house.
You do whatever you want or need to.
And if any issues do come up, we can talk through them.
That sounds good.
On that note, is there anything you want to tell me?
Just don't up and disappear on me, okay?
Okay.
I understand.
I won't disappear on you.
I love you.
Good.
Love you.